乱世儿女
第一部
雷蒙?巴瑞
如何获得巴瑞林顿的头衔
与上流生活
Gentlemen, cock your pistols.
各位，扣上扳机
Barry's father had been bred,
like many sons of genteel families...
巴瑞的父亲在教养很好的家庭长大
...to the profession of the law.
在律师的专业上
There is no doubt he would've made an eminent figure
in his profession...
无疑的，他是最优秀的
...had he not been killed in a duel...
若是他买马的时候，没有因为争执而被杀的话
...which arose over the purchase of some horses.
Barry's mother, after her husband's death...
巴瑞的妈妈，在丈夫过世后
...lived in such a way as to defy slander.
如圣人一样过生活
Many a man who had been charmed by the spinster...
许多受到她吸引的人
...renewed his offers to the widow.
重新向这寡妇求婚
But she refused all proposals of marriage...
但她拒绝了所有要求
...declaring that she lived only for her son...
她说要全心全力照顾儿子
...and the memory of her departed saint.
和她过世丈夫的记忆里
First love!  What a change it makes in a lad.
初恋！改变一个年轻人
What a magnificent secret it is
he carries with him!
他心里多棒的一个秘密
The tender passion gushes out of a man's heart.
他心里面蔓延着柔情
He loves as a bird sings...
他喜欢听鸟歌唱
...or a rose blows from nature.
看玫瑰花开
Killarney.
克怀根
Now, what shall it be?
现在要怎么办？
Turn around and face the wall.
转过身别看
The object of Barry's attention,
巴瑞所注意的
and......the cause of his early troubles...
与引起他早期麻烦的因素
...was his cousin, Nora Brady by name.
就是他表亲诺拉布莱迪
I have hidden my neck ribbon
somewhere on my person.
我把丝带藏在身上
If you find it, you can have it.
如果你找到，就是你的
You are free to look anywhere for it.
随便你怎么搜
I will think little of you，if you do not find it.
如果你找不到，我就再也不想你了
I cannot find it.
我找不到
You haven't looked properly.
你没有好好找
I cannot find it.
我找不到
I'll give you a hint.
给你一个提示
I feel the ribbon.
我感觉得到丝带
Why are you trembling?
你为什么发抖？
At the pleasure of finding the ribbon.
因为我找到丝带很开心
Liar.
胡说
About this time the United Kingdom
当时英国
was greatly excited... ...by the threat...
因为法国可能入侵，而全国澎湃
...of a French invasion.
The noblemen and people of condition...
贵族与士绅
...loyally raised regiments...
开始招募士兵
...to resist the invaders.
准备驱赶入侵者
Their scarlet coats and swaggering airs
filled Barry with envy.
他们的红大衣和气派，让巴瑞很羡慕
Brady Town sent a company to join...
布莱迪家族派人加入
...the Kilwangen Regiment
of which John Quin was the Captain.
约翰昆恩队长的克里维德军团
The whole country was alive
with war's alarums...
整个国家期待战争
...the kingdoms ringing
with military music.
军队行动声音弥漫整个国家
Redmond, what is the matter?
雷蒙，怎么了？
Were you obliged to dance five times with Captain Quin?
你一定要和约翰昆恩跳五次舞吗？
I don't care a fig for Captain Quin.
我才不在乎约翰昆恩
He dances prettily,
and is a pleasant rattle of a man.
他舞技很好，让人觉得很舒服
He looks well in his regimentals.
穿起军服很帅
He asked me to dance.
他请我跳舞
How could I refuse him?
我怎么拒绝的了他？
But you refused me.
但你拒绝我
I can dance with you any day.
我可以每天跟你跳
To dance with my cousin looks as though
I could find no other partner.
跟我表亲跳舞，意味着我不能找别人
Besides, Captain Quin is a man.
而且，昆恩队长是个男人
You're only a boy and penniless.
而你是没钱的小子
If I meet him again, you will find out who is the best man.
如果我再遇见他，你就知道谁是男人
I'll fight him Captain as he is.
即是他是队长，我也会跟他打
Oh, don't be so silly!
别傻了
I mean it.
我是认真的
But Captain Quin is known as a valiant soldier.
昆恩队长据说是个勇敢的战士
It is mighty well of you to fight yokels...
你打些当地街头小混混还很容易
...but to fight an Englishman is a different matter.
但打英国人又另当别论
You best have him take you home.
你最好让他送你回家
Redmond!
雷蒙！
Barry resolved never to see Nora again.
巴瑞决定再也不见诺拉
But such resolutions,
steadfastly held for a whole week...
但这决定只维持了一星期
...are abandoned in a few moments of despair.
因为沮丧而放弃了
No, Nora, no, except for you and four others...
不，诺拉，除了你和其他四个
...I vow before all the gods my heart...
我发誓
...has never felt the soft flame.
没有爱的感觉
Ah, you men, you men, John...
你们
...your passion's not equal to ours.
你们的激情跟我们的不同
We are like some plant I've read of.
我们像是我读过的一种植物
We bear but one flower and then we die.
只开一次花，然后死去
You, you, you mean you...
你是说
...never felt an inclination for another?
你不会对其他人有兴趣？
Never, my John.
不会，亲爱的约翰
How can you ask such a question?
你怎么问这么问题？
Oh, darling Norelia!
亲爱的诺里亚
Nora was chaperoned by her brothers，Mick and Ulick...
诺拉身边总有她兄弟，米克与乌里克陪着
...whose interests would be affected...
因为她与昆恩队长的关系，他们想藉故攀上
...by the favourable outcome of her affair with Quin.
Redmond, how nice to see you.
雷蒙，很高兴见到你
Redmond!
雷蒙！
How could you do this to me?
你怎么可以这么对我？
Redmond, what's the matter?
怎么了？
What are you saying?
你说什么？
I think this might be the moment to return something to you.
我想该把你的东西还给你了
Thank you, Redmond.
雷蒙，谢谢
I must have forgotten it.
我一定是忘记了
Yes, you did.
对
Captain Quin, may I introduce my cousin, Redmond Barry.
昆恩队长，这是我表亲，雷蒙巴瑞
Miss Brady, it would appear...
布莱迪小姐
...you both have something private to discuss.
似乎你们两位有私事要商量
It would be best for me to withdraw.
我不在场比较妥当
Captain Quin, I have nothing private
to discuss with my cousin.
昆恩队长，我跟他没有什么重要的事
Miss Brady, it appears you have a great deal to discuss.
布莱迪小姐，你们好像有很重要的事需要谈谈
Captain Quin, he don't signify any more
than my parrot or lapdog.
昆恩队长，他对我而言只不过像只鹦鹉
Indeed!
是啊！
Are you in the habit of giving...
而你有习惯
...intimate articles of your clothing to your parrot or lapdog?
把你的亲密的衣服给你的鹦鹉？
Mayn't I give a bit of ribbon to my own cousin?
我不能把丝带给我表亲？
You're welcome, miss.
可以，小姐
As many yards as you like.
几尺都可以
When ladies make presents to gentlemen,
it's time for other gentlemen to retire.
这样的话，我还是先回避好了
I wish you both a good day.
祝你们愉快
Jack Quin!
杰克昆恩！
What's the matter?
什么事？
I'll tell you, sir.
先生，我告诉你
I've had enough of Miss Brady and your lrish ways.
我讨厌布莱迪小姐和你这爱尔兰的把戏
What is it?
什么把戏？
We'll accustom you to lrish ways,
or we'll adopt English ones.
我们会按照爱尔兰的方式解决，或者以英国传统解决
It is not the English way for ladies to have two lovers.
根据传统，一个女子不能有二个爱人
And so, I'll thank you to pay me the sum you owe me.
所以我要你将欠我的钱还给我
And I resign all claims to this young lady.
我会退出
If she fancies schoolboys, let her take 'em, sir.
如果她喜欢小男生，就这样吧
You're joking!
你开玩笑
I never was more earnest.
我从来没有这么认真过
John, wait.
约翰，等等
Meddling brat!
笨小子！
Your hand is in everybody's pie!
你什么闲事都管
What business have you to quarrel with a gentleman of substance?
你跟那位绅士有何好吵的？
Redmond, me boy, take a seat.
雷蒙，坐下
Mrs. Brady and ladies, if you please.
布莱迪女士，女士们，注意一下
This sort of toast is drunk too seldom in my family...
在这个家族很少这样举杯
...and you'll please to receive it with all honours.
希望你能欣然接受
Here's to Captain and Mrs. John Quin
and a long life to them.
敬队长，队长夫人，祝他们长命百岁
Kiss her, Jack, for faith you've got a treasure.
杰克，亲她，你获得珍宝了
Come on, Jack.
快，杰克
There's the man!
这才是真正男子汉
A long and happy life together.
敬永远幸福的家庭生活
Thank you.
谢谢你
Redmond!
雷蒙！
Here's my toast to you, Captain John Quin.
敬你，约翰昆恩队长
Redmond, how dare you behave like that in my house!
雷蒙，你怎么在我家里这么没礼貌
Mrs. Brady, take the children out.
布莱迪女士，把这小鬼带出去
My dear fellow, are you all right?
亲爱的，你没事吧？
In heaven's name, what does all the row mean?
老天，这是什么意思？
The fact is, sir...
事实上
...the young monkey's in love with Nora.
那小砘锵不杜道
He found her and the Captain in the garden today.
他今天看到她和队长在花园
Now he's for murdering Jack Quin.
现在他要跟杰克昆恩决斗
Mr. Brady, I've been insulted grossly in this house.
布莱迪先生，我在这里被污辱了
I'm not satisfied with these ways of going on.
我不满你们的态度
I'm an Englishman!
And a man of property!
我是英国人、富豪
And this impudent young swine...
这蛮横的年轻人
...should be horsewhipped!
应该遭受鞭刑
Mr. Quin can have satisfaction any time he pleases...
昆恩先生随时能获得满意的答覆
只要他在巴瑞维尔跟雷蒙决斗
...by calling on Redmond Barry,  Esquire of Barryville.
I'll see the boy home.
我跟那小子说
A pretty day's work, Master Redmond.
好，雷蒙先生
Knowing your uncle is distressed for money...
你了解你叔叔急需用钱吗
...trying to break off a match which
will bring L1,500 a year into the family....
你想要捣乱他一年收入1500英镑的收入？
Quin has promised to pay off the L4,000
which is bothering your uncle.
昆恩答应付你叔叔4000英镑的债
He takes a girl without a penny...
他分文不取的接受她
...a girl that's flinging herself
at the head of every man in these parts.
这位到处拈花惹草的女人
And missing them all!
全都不介意！
And you, who ought to be attached
to your uncle as to your father....
你应该如尊敬你父亲一样尊敬你叔叔
I am.
我是啊
And this is the return
you make for his kindness?
你是这样回报他的吗？
Didn't he harbour you when your father died?
当你父亲过世时，不是他照顾你？
Hasn't he given you and your mother a fine house, rent free?
他不是不收半毛钱，让你和你妈住？
Mark this, and come what will of it...
听我说，不管你怎么想
...I will fight the man who pretends
the hand of Nora Brady.
我要跟抢走诺拉的人决斗
I'll follow him if it's into the church and fight him there.
我甚至会跟他到教堂决斗
I'll have his blood, or he'll have mine.
不是他死就我死
Faith, and I believe ye!
我相信
I never saw a lad more game in me life.
我没见过你这么有勇气的孩子
Give me a kiss, me boy.
亲我一下，孩子
You're after me own soul.
你跟我一样
As long as I live, you shall never want a friend or a second.
只要我活着，你找不到更好的朋友
Will you take my message to him?
And arrange a meeting?
你答应了吗？会安排决斗？
Well, if it must be, it must.
如果你要的话，就举行吧
Look here, Redmond, me boy,
this is a silly business.
听着，雷蒙，这很笨
The girl will marry Quin, mark my words.
这女孩会嫁给昆恩，相信我
And as sure as she does, you'll forget her.
你很快就会忘记她
You're but a boy and Quin is willing to consider you as such.
你是个小孩，昆恩也把你当小孩看
Right, Quin?
是吗，昆恩？
Yes.
是的
Now, Dublin's a fine place.
都柏林是好地方
If you've a mind to ride there
and see the town for a month...
如果你可以骑马到那里去逛一个月的话
...here's ten guineas at your service.
这里的钱让你当盘缠
Will that satisfy you, Captain Quin?
昆恩队长，你满意吗？
Yes, if Mr. Barry will apologize and go to Dublin...
是的，如果巴瑞先生道歉，并且前往都柏林
...I will consider the whole affair honourably settled.
我会考虑把这不当一回事
Say you're sorry, Redmond.
雷蒙，说道歉
You can easily say that.
很简单
I'm not sorry.
我不道歉
And I'll not apologize.
不要
And I'd as soon go to Dublin as to hell.
我宁愿死也不愿去都柏林
Then there's nothing else for it.
我们之间没什么好说的了
God bless you.
上帝保佑你吧
This isn't my pistol.
这不是我的手枪
It's all right, it's one of mine.
别担心，这是我的
Yours will serve, if it's needed, for the next round.
如果要的话，下一轮我会给你你的手枪
Good luck, Redmond.
祝你好运，雷蒙
Gentlemen...
各位
...cock your pistols.
举起手枪
Gentlemen...
各位
...aim your pistols.
瞄准目标
One.
一
Two.
二
Three.
三
Is he dead?
他死了吗？
Quite dead.
活不了
This has been a sad day's work for our family.
我们家悲惨的一天
Ye've robbed us of 1,500 a year.
你剥夺了我们一年1500英镑的收入
Now you'd better ride off，before the Police are up.
警察来前，你最好走吧
They'd wind of this before we left Kilwangen.
我们前往克怀根前就会东窗事发
Come on, Redmond, I'll go home with you.
快，雷蒙，我跟你回去
How different Barry's fate might have been...
巴瑞应该会有不同的境遇
...had he not fallen in love with Nora...
要是他没爱上诺拉
...and had he not flung the wine in Captain Quin's face.
没有把酒丢在昆恩队长脸上
But he was destined to be a wanderer.
但命运都注定好了
And the battle with Quin set him on his travels at an early age...
与昆恩的决斗迫使他的早年
...as you shall soon see.
就步上你即将知道的结果
The boy must go into hiding
for a short time, anyway.
那小子暂时一定躲起来了
Dublin's the best place for him.
都柏林最适合他躲
He can stay there 'til matters have blown over.
他可以待在那儿避过锋头
But the child has never been away from home before.
那孩子从来没有离开家过
Wouldn't he be as safe here?
他在这里不安全吗？
I wish that were true, Aunt Belle.
我希望这里能够安全，贝尔阿姨
But the Bailiffs may be on their way already.
但法警可能已经出发啦
Now, Dublin is five days ride away from here.
都柏林离这里有五天的路程
There's not a soul who'll know him there.
那里不会有人认得他
I don't want to harp on unpleasant matters...
我不想往坏处想
...but you do know what can happen to him if he's taken.
但你知道他们抓到他的话会怎么处置他？
I'll be all right.
我会没事的
I'll be all right in Dublin, Mother.
妈，我在都柏林不会有事
No lad with liberty for the first time,
and 20 guineas in his pocket...
那些头一次体会自由的人，手边还有二十基尼
...is very sad.
不会太难过
Barry rode towards Dublin thinking not so much of. ..
巴瑞前往都柏林，沿路不太思念
...the kind mother left alone, and the home behind him...
留在家乡的母亲
...but of tomorrow and all the wonders it would bring.
而是明天，以及往后的迷惘
Excuse me, miss.
小姐，对不起
Would it be possible to have a drink of water?
我可以喝杯水吗？
Good day to you, young sir.
年轻人，你好
Good day.
很好
Will you join us in a drink?
你要加入我们喝一杯吗？
No, thank you.
不用了，谢谢
Would you like something to eat?
要不要吃点东西？
That's very kind of you,  but I have to be on my way.
谢谢你的好意，但我要走了
Thank you.
谢谢
Goodbye.
再见
Excuse me, sir.
先生，对不起
Good morning again, young sir.
早，年轻人
Don't even think about it.
你跑不掉了
Get down off that horse.
下马
Raise your hands above your head, please.
手举到头上
Come forward.
向前站
Stop.
停
How do you do.  I'm Captain Feeney.
嗨，我是芬尼队长
Captain Feeney!
芬尼队长？
Captain Feeney, at your service.
芬尼队长替你服务
The Captain Feeney?
你是芬尼队长？
None other.
正是在下
May I introduce you to my son...Seamus?
我能介绍你我儿子辛姆斯？
To whom do I have the honour of speaking?
我能荣幸知道你名字吗？
My name's Redmond Barry.
我叫雷蒙巴瑞
How do you do, Mr. Barry?
巴瑞先生，你好
Now we must get onto the more
regrettable stage of our brief acquaintance.
现在面对相识的不幸了
Turn around and keep your hands
high above your head, please.
转过身，手举到头上
There must be 20 guineas in gold here, Father.
20基尼金币
You seem to be a very well set up，young gentleman, sir.
你好像是个有钱人
Captain Feeney, that's all the money
my mother had in the world.
芬尼队长，这是我母亲仅有的财产
Mightn't I keep it?
我能留下吗？
I'm just one step ahead of the Law myself.
我也在逃亡
I killed an English Officer in a duel, and
I'm going to Dublin until things cool down.
我决斗中杀了一个英国军官，现在要去都柏林避风头
Mr. Barry...
巴瑞先生
...in my profession we hear many such stories.
我听过好几遍相同的故事
Yours is the most intriguing and touching
I've heard in weeks.
你的是我最常听见过的诡计
Nevertheless, I cannot grant your request.
然而我无法满足你的要求
But, I'll tell you what I will do.
我告诉你我会怎么做
I'll allow you to keep those fine boots,
which normally I would have for myself.
我会让你留着你的靴子，一般我都自己留下的
The next town is only five miles away.
下个城镇只有五英哩
And I suggest you now start walking.
你马上滚
Mightn't I keep my horse?
我不能留下我的马？
I would like to oblige you...
我很想给你
...but, people like us must be able
to travel faster than our clients.
但我们要跑得比追我们的人快
Good day, young sir.
祝你愉快
You can put down your hands now, Mr. Barry.
巴瑞先生，你的手可以放下了
Gale's Regiment of Foot, commanded
by Lieutenant General Charles Gale...
中将盖尔引导的步兵团
...which has distinguished itself
during the recent troubles...
想要在最近的战斗中拔卓而出
...wants several men to supply the places of those veterans...
需要新人替换老将
...who have deserved to be pensioned
at one shilling a day.
每天一先令
All clever young fellows who are free and able...
所有自由又有能力的年轻人
...and are ambitious of becoming gentlemen
by bearing arms...
想成为武装男人
...are hereby invited to meet the Recruiting Officer...
都可以到招募官那儿
...who promises that they shall meet
with every encouragement...
只要能力受到肯定
...that merit and good behaviour
can entitle them to.
都会被接受
Those meeting the qualifications
will immediately receive...
合格的马上就会获得
...His Majesty's Royal Bounty of one and a half guineas...
皇家奖赏一块半基尼
...with complete clothing, arms and accoutrements.
外加衣服，武器军火
King George and Old England forever.
乔治王与英国万岁
For a young man in difficulty...
对一个处于困境的年轻人
...who had killed a man in a duel and
was anxious to find refuge from the Law...
决斗时杀了人，成为逃犯
...the chance to earn distinction in the European wars...
在欧洲战争上唯一获得成名的机会
...seemed a stroke of good fortune.
好像变成送来的好运
And King George needed men too much
to heed from whence they came.
乔治王需要战士，不管何种出身
Hey, lad! Lad!
嗨，小子
Can I have a new beaker?
This one is full of grease.
我可以换个新杯子吗？这杯子都是油
Covered in grease!
Give the gentleman a towel and a basin of turtle soup.
拿块布给他，再给他一大锅汤
If you want to vex him, ask him about his wife...
如果你要调侃他，问他他太太的事
...the washerwoman, who beats him.
她打过他
Mr. Toole, is it a towel of your wife's washing?
多尔先生，这是你太太洗的衣服吗？
They say she wipes your face often with one.
听说她常常拿衣服打你
Ask him why he wouldn't see her yesterday
when she came here.
问他昨天她来的时候，为什么避不见面？
Mr. Toole, why did you hide
when Mrs. Toole came to visit you?
多尔先生，为什么昨天你太太来的时候，你躲着不见面
Afraid of getting your ears boxed?
你怕她赏你耳光？
Gentlemen, you may fight it out with fists if you choose.
各位，想打就打
We'll form a square for that purpose.
大家可以围成一圈
Gentlemen, step this way, please.
各位，麻烦，过来这里
Shake hands.
握手
Take your stance.
就位
No biting, kicking or scratching.
不准咬、踢，也不准抓
The last man to remain standing is the winner.
最后还能屹立不倒的就算获胜
Gentlemen, commence fighting, now!
各位，拳赛开始
Barry's training continued at the camp.
巴瑞继续在营内受训
Within a month he was transformed
into a proper young soldier.
一个月后成为真正的士兵
The Regiment's strength was steadily increased...
军团随着一些原本要加入
...by the arrival of other troops...
德国军队的士兵陆续加入
...in preparation for joining
their armies fighting in Germany.
整个势力迅速壮大
One occasion...
一件令人愉快事
...brought the welcome appearance
of his second in the fatal duel...
改变命运的第二个人
...Captain Grogan.
高根队长
It would have helped if we'd known
what had become of you.
能知道你的过去吗？
Didn't you think of writing to your mother?
你不想写家书回去？
Of course.
当然想
But the shame I felt of losing her money...
但我没有脸写，因为我弄丢她给的钱
...my father's sword and pistols....
还有我父亲的剑和枪
I couldn't tell her.
我不能告诉她
She wouldn't care about those things.
她不会在乎这些
You are her only concern.
她只会在乎你
Tonight you must write her a proper letter.
今天晚上好好写封信给她
Tell her that you're safe and well.
告诉她你很安全，一切很好
I will.
我会的
Is Miss Brady well?
布莱迪小姐好吗？
There are only six Miss Bradys now.
现在只剩6位布莱迪小姐
Has something happened to Nora?
诺拉发生了什么事吗？
She took on so about your going away...
她很在意你的离去
...that she had to console herself with a husband.
然后就结婚了
She is now Mrs. John Quin.
现在她是约翰昆恩太太
Mrs. John Quin?
约翰昆恩太太？
Was there another John Quin?
有另一位约翰昆恩？
No.
不
The same, me boy. He recovered from his wound.
同一个人，孩子，他康复了
The shot you hit him with could not hurt him.
It was made of tow.
你开枪的子弹伤不了他，用麻做的
Tow?
麻？
The Bradys wouldn't let you kill
1,500 a year out of the family.
布莱迪不会让你破坏一年一千五百英镑的收入
The plan of the duel was arranged
in order to get you out of the way.
你的对手用这种计划让你离开
The cowardly Quin couldn't be brought to marry...
他们没法促成婚事
...from fear of you.
因为昆恩怕你
但你的确
But hit him you certainly did, me lad.
With a fine thick plugget of tow.
用麻球打过他
He was so frightened,  it took him an hour to come to.
他非常害怕，一小时后才醒来
Are you in want of cash?
你需要钱吗？
You may draw on me.
For I got a couple of hundred from your uncle.
我从你叔叔那儿收到二百块
While that lasts, you shall never want.
你就收下吧
It would require a great historian to explain the causes...
需要个伟大的历史学家来解释
...of the Seven Years' War in Europe...
巴瑞的军团在欧洲
...to which Barry's regiment was now on it's way.
历经七年的战役
Let it suffice to say, that England and Prussia were allies...
单是英国和普鲁士联盟
...and at war against...
对抗
...France, Sweden, Russia and Austria.
法国，瑞典，苏联和奥地利就够了
Barry's first taste ofbattle...
巴瑞遭遇到的第一场战役
...was only a skirmish against
a rearguard of Frenchmen...
就是与埋伏在英国军团必经之
...who occupied an orchard beside a road...
路上邻近小果园的法国军团
...down which the English main force wished to pass.
展开一场遭遇战
Though this encounter is not recorded in any history book...
虽然战役没有写进历史记录
...it was memorable enough for those who took part.
但参加的人都记得
我给你一百基尼
剩下的玩牌都输掉了
小子，亲我吧
我们以后不会再见面了
坐在舒服的摇椅上
想着光荣的战役很简单
但当你亲眼目睹
又是另一回事了
他朋友死后
巴瑞对于军对荣耀的想法开始改
如何逃离
他还要服役六年的军队
大家都谈论骑士时代
但记得他们带领的
都是强盗土匪
凭着破烂的武器
这些伟大的战士，与国王
赢了战役
巴瑞现在的境遇
应该是最悲惨的
但命运注定
他不需要军旅生涯不会太久
一件令人意想不到的事
让他非常不寻常的离开军队
佛莱迪，希望你别生我的气
但我得说一件
你不会感到开心的事
什么事？
你得先说好
你不会生气
强纳生，别这样！
你先挑起来的
什么事？
我又要离开了
大约二星期
你说真的吗？
是的，没办法
这次要上哪去？
到布莱梅，把重要消息
传给亨利王子
但你保证上次
已经是最后一次
我知道，我也想遵守诺言
但庞特斯比
坚持要我去
这是逃离军队
绝佳的机会
会经过几个普鲁士
占领的地方
而这位军官的军服和文件
让他经过时不会遭到
任何怀疑
而带着他背叛的消息离开
我们还有一点时间
你生我的气吗？
我不会生你的气太久
强纳生
像这种时候我才发现
你对我来说有多亲密
没有你我的生活
会多空虚
佛德瑞克！
巴瑞看见了普鲁士军团的制服
非常开心
表示他已经离开
英国占领的区域
他本想要前往荷兰
一个欧洲少数几个中立的国家
再从那里
设法回到故乡
当他骑在马上
巴瑞深深感觉到
决心要过个绅士的生活
小姐，对不起
什么事
早安
你会说英语吗？
一点点
我整天没有吃东西了
附近有吃的地方吗？
没有
到达葛伦堡前
都没有餐厅
你住在附近吗？
是的
你能帮我弄点吃的？
我可以付你钱
好的
男的还是女的
男的
叫什么名字？
彼得
几岁？
一岁
他父亲呢？
在哪里？
是的
打仗去了
去多久？
我听不懂
什么？
很久
春天就去了
你一个人过生活
一定很辛苦
没错
身处战地一定很危险
我是个军官
尽我的本分
你有时候会觉得…
寂寞吗？
有时候会的
你说你叫什么名字？
费肯汉中尉
不是，我是说…
你的名字
名字？
强纳生
你愿意跟我
在一起吗？
几天就好？
好
再见，可人儿莉贞
再见，雷蒙
我爱你
我也爱你
保重
愿上帝与你同在
一个将心交给军人的女人
一定要准备
常常更换爱人
否则她的生活会很悲伤
莉贞的心就像是邻近的乡村
在巴瑞出现前
遭受到战火多次攻击与复原
在这五年的战争中
费德瑞克的军团
耗尽男性人口
为了雇用特别的人
甚至犯罪绑架也在所不惜
以便维持军团的光辉
长官，晚安
我是帕兹朵夫队长
你是谁？
盖尔步兵团
费肯汉中尉
你好
有何贵事？
我身上携有重要消息
需要通过
你要去哪？
布莱梅
中尉，你一定是迷路了
布莱梅在另一个方向
你确定吗？
是的
怎么可能？
我的助理没有时间
准备详细的地图给我
我了解
中尉，别在意
你有身分证明文件吗？
当然有
我可以看看吗？
可以
谢谢
中尉，谢谢你
希望没有造成你的不便
不会
既然我们顺路同一个方向
今晚我能提供你食宿的地方
还有一张仔细点的地图？
队长，你人真好
我有幸能够接受款待
他们非常善待巴瑞
他们问他种种英国的问题
他凭着自己想像
尽量好好回答
他描述着国王和首相
吹嘘说柏林的英国大使
是他的叔叔
甚至可以给帕兹多夫
写封推荐信函
招待他的主人
他的回答
但马上技巧的巴结
询问巴瑞
我对英国认识很少
除了说你们是
世界上最勇敢的国家
我们很幸运
有你们这种同盟伙伴
费肯汉中尉
敬我们两国之间的友谊
敬我们两个伟大的国家
你很幸运
明天就你到布莱梅了
一位欧洲最美的女士
住在那儿
你能帮我带个口信？
很乐意
对了，你要把口信交给谁？
威廉森将军
威廉森将军？
波斯佛威廉森将军？
正是
逮捕这砘
逮捕我？帕兹朵夫队长…
我是个英国军官
你是个大骗子
还是个逃兵
我今天早上就怀疑你
你的谎言证实了一切
你说你带口信给
已经死了十个月的将军
你说柏林的英国大使
是你的叔叔
叫做欧葛莱帝这种奇怪的名字
你要加入我们的军队？
还是投降？
我自愿
普鲁士的军队比英国军队还糟糕
士兵的生活充满危险
军官滥用处罚权力
低阶军官常常受到鞭打
更严重的
到伤残或死亡
七年战后
在普鲁士军官暴政下
军队以风纪闻名
但军队大多是由
社会低下阶层
或是从欧洲据来的人所组成
最糟的是，巴瑞
落入最烂的军队
各种侮辱都有
救命！
救我出去
上校表示
国王对他很满意
在奥多夫战役中
整个军团的表现
以及巴瑞下士英勇拯救
帕兹多夫队长的行为
获得二个腓德烈克金币
巴瑞下士，往前八步
前进！
巴瑞下士
你是个勇敢的士兵
顾家的好男人
但你很懒散
没有纪律
影响其他人的士气
除了你的勇气
你一无是处
我希望上校弄错了
我只是加入不好的军队
不是行为不良
我没有朋友或上司
证明我能做得更好